<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>To the right honourable the house of Commons assembled in Parliament. The humble petition of Thomas Man  ...</title>
            <author>Stationers' Company (London, England)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1621</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 3 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A72821</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 16786.6</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S125114</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99898856</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99898856</idno>
            <idno type="VID">151069</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A72821)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 151069)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 1997:41)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>To the right honourable the house of Commons assembled in Parliament. The humble petition of Thomas Man  ...</title>
                  <author>Stationers' Company (London, England)</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1621]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Against the patent of Roger Wood and Thomas Symcock for the sole printing of paper and parchment on one side--STC.</note>
                  <note>Imprint from STC.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Guildhall Library, London, England.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Man, Thomas, d. 1625 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Symcock, Thomas, fl. 1619-1629 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Wood, Roger, fl. 1619-1629 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Printers --  England --  London --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Printing --  England --  London --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>London (England) --  History --  17th century --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2008-08</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2008-11</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-04</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-04</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="petition">
            <pb n="68" facs="tcp:151069:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 5 -->
            <head>To the right Honourable the Houſe of Commons, aſſembled in Parliament.</head>
            <head type="sub">The humble petition of Thomas Man, Humfrey Lownes, Clement Knight, Thomas Daniel, Thomas Purfoot, William Jaggard, John Beale, Nicolas Bourne, William Ients, Simon Stafford, William Lugger, John Dawſon, Nathaniel Newbery, Iohn Trundle, Henry Goſſon, George Norton, Iohn Speed, George Humble, John Tappe, Chriſtofer Purſet, John Wright, <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>u<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>hbert Wright, George Latham, Iohn Mariott, Iohn Griſman, Thomas Langly, John White, Phillip Birch, George Lowe, Richard Sharſakers, Laurence Dudley, with many others.</head>
            <p>Whereas Roger Ward and Thomas Simcocke, for the benefit of Marine Boiſloret (a Frenchman) haue of late obtained from the Kings moſt excellent Maieſty vnder the great Seale of England, a Priuiledge to imprint, vtter, &amp; ſell, all and all manner of Briefes of Letters Pattents for loſſes by fier or water, all Jndentures for Apprentices, all indentures for Waterworkes, all bonds and Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cognizances, all licenſes to gather by, licenſes to marry, licenſes for Victualers, all acquittances, all articles for viſitacions of Biſhops and Officials, all billes for teaching ſchollers, billes for Phiſitions, and all play-billes, all paſports, Charts, Epitaphs, portractures and pictures whatſoeuer, and all other things printed, and hereafter to be printed vp<gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>n oneſide only of a ſheete or ſheetes of paper, or a ſkin or ſkinnes of parchment, as mort at large by the ſaid grant may appeare.</p>
            <p>Now may it pleaſe this Honorable Aſſembly to be enformed, That the Peti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioners reſpectiuely haue euer had the free vſe of printing theſe things, from the firſt times the ſame were imprinted, vntill the ſeuenteenth yeare of his Maieſties happie Raigne. And if the benefit thereof be taken from the petitioners, it will not onely be a great hinderance vnto them who haue beene brought vp in this Art, and maintained themſelues and their ſeuerall families thereby, But alſo to all other his Maieſties louing ſubiects that haue occaſion to vſe any of the things mentioned in the ſaid Letters Patents.</p>
            <p>The humble ſute of the Petitioners is, that this Honorable Aſſembly will take ſuch order, that the Petitioners may haue free liberty to imprint the premiſes, as formerly they haue done, before the ſaid Letters Patents were granted,</p>
            <closer>And they ſhall euer pray, &amp;c.</closer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
